Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
火鸟字幕合并器SubindexV0.5
Created time 11.06.20 15:42:19
为了让我接受更好的教育
It had been a year since my mother sent me
老妈把我送到Corleone中学读了一年了
to Corleone Junior High for a better education.
笨蛋
Jerk.
噢 我正在接受更好的教育 没错
Oh, I was getting a better education, all right.
苦难教育
An education in misery.
我讨厌上课
I was tired of my classes.
印嘎 宾嘎 宾嘎 巴嘎
Inga, binga, binga, bunga.
Chris 你来自哪个部落?
Chris, what tribe are you from?
我不知道!
I don't know!
我拼命想睡一会
I still struggled to get sleep.
- 安 妈妈 - 晚安 宝贝
- Night, Ma. - Night, baby.
Chris赶紧起床! 是时候要上学了
Chris, get your butt up! It's time to go to school.
最糟糕的是 人人都讨厌我
And worst of all, everybody hated me.
小屁孩讨厌我
The kids hated me.
老师讨厌我
The teachers hated me.
连食堂大妈也讨厌我
Even the lunch ladies hated me.
在Corleone唯一的好事就是遇见Greg
The only good thing that happened to me at Corleone was meeting Greg.
嘿 想去打电动吗?
Hey, you want to go over to the arcade?
- 他们有了炸弹人 - 我不喜欢那里
- They've got Ms. Pacman. - I don't like it over there.
嗨 你是Chris 对吗?
Hi. You're Chris, right?
是 干嘛?
Yeah, why?
我只是想让你知道
I just wanted to let you know I think it's pretty lame
人人都那样对你真的很过分
how everybody's been treating you.
对以前我啥也没说而抱歉
Sorry I didn't say anything before now.
没关系 谢谢
That's all right. Thanks.
嘿 我要去电动室和朋友们会合玩炸弹人
Hey, I'm meeting some friends over at the arcade to play some Ms. Pacman.
你想来吗?
You want to come?
- 不 他不想去 - 我可没说
- Nah, he doesn't want to. - I didn't say that.
来吧
Come on.
你也来啊
You can come, too.
最终还是有人眷顾了我
Finally someone was being nice to me.
我会在炸弹人里虐你
I'm going to beat your butt in Ms. Pacman.
噢 走着瞧咯
Oh, we'll see about that.
惊喜 小金刚
Surprise, Donkey Kong.
我就知道没有那么便宜的事
I knew it was too good to be true.
- Greg! - 快跑 你这小笨蛋
- Greg! - Run away, you little idiot.
扁他!
Get him!
尝尝这个 你这小阿飞
Take that, you little punk.
噢 我恨他
Oh, I hate him.
笨蛋黑鬼
Silly Negro.
你知道吗?
You know what?
我觉得是这个黑鬼离开这学校的时候了
I think it's time for this silly Negro to get out of this school.
1x18 Everybody Hates Corleone
Transcript: Raceman Adaptation: Sixe
人人都恨克里斯 第1季 第18集 "人人都恨克里昂"
天哪 发生什么事了?
Oh, my God. What happened to you?
妈妈 我再也不想回那学校了
Mom, I am not going back to that school.
好吧 等等 怎么回事?
All right, now, wait a minute. What's going on?
我讨厌Corleone
I hate Corleone.
我不合群 没人喜欢我
I don't fit in. Nobody likes me.
经常累的半死
I'm always tired,
几乎每天都有人来作弄我
and almost every day somebody is picking on me.
Chris 你不能因此而放弃接受良好教育
Chris, you cannot let that stop you from getting a good education.
我们又不是送你去讨人喜欢的 宝贝
We didn't send you over there to be liked, baby.
说的对
Got that right.
妈妈 我在那唯一学到的就是逃跑
Mom, the only thing I'm learning over there is how to get jumped on.
我怎么就不能去桑福德中学呢?
How come I can't go to Lamont Sanford Junior High?
- 就隔几个街区而已 - 不行
- It's only a few blocks away. - Mm-mm, no.
你不能去这附近的学校
You are not going to school in this neighborhood.
你还记得去年有个女孩在玛拉吉中学被人捅了一刀吗?
You remember that girl that got stabbed last year at Marla Gibbs High School?
Chris 桑福德里都是痞子小青年和少年犯
Chris, Sanford has nothing but juvenile delinquents and future convicts.
一个人把我出卖给便衣而被判了10年
A man just got ten years because he sold me to an undercover cop.
那么我是?
What am I?
大麻 可卡因 海洛英 还是快克?
Weed, cocaine, heroin or crack?
- Rachel - 是快克
- Rachel. - Crack.
- 但是妈妈 - 但是没用 Chris
- But Mom... - But nothing, Chris.
还有你是怎么弄的满身油漆?
And how did you get paint all over you, anyway?
我去店里玩炸弹人
I went to the store to go play Ms. Pacman.
啊哈! 瞧见没?
Aha! Ah! See there?
要是你一开始就不去那里
See, now, had you not been there in the first place,
你就不会搞的一团糟
you wouldn't be in this mess.
我不断的讲 家和学校两点一线
I keep telling you, come straight home from school.
或许你现在该听我的话了
Maybe now you'll listen to me.
听着 我知道你不喜欢去Corleone
Look, I know you don't like going to Corleone.
但是万事多磨难
But everything is not supposed to be easy.
你明白吗?
You understand me?
上楼去把衣服脱了吧
Now, go upstairs and get out of those clothes.
是的 妈妈
Yes, ma'am.
他咋了 看起来像个湿嗒嗒的小丑
What happened to him? He looks like a wet mime.
没事 他在学校出了点意外
Nothing, he got in an accident at school.
我妈从来不愿意告诉爸爸坏消息
My mother never liked to bother my father with bad news.
像上次Tonya被公车给撞了
Like the time Tonya got hit by a bus.
Tonya怎么了?
What happened to Tonya?
没事
Nothing.
还有次Drew的腿给截了
Or the time Drew got his legs cut off.
- Drew怎么了? - 没啥
- What happened to Drew? - Nothing.
你在乐呵个啥?
What are you so happy about?
你记得我去应聘鱼市场的工作吗?
You know that job I applied for down at the fish market?
- 嗯 - 我被聘了!
- Yeah. - I got it!
噢 宝贝 真棒!
Oh, baby, that's great!
恭喜啊
Congratulations.
嗯
Yeah.
比俺两份工资加起来还付的多
It pays more than my other two jobs combined.
真棒! 我要去逛街!
That's great! I get to shop!
这些年头一回我只需要打一份工
Man, for the first time in years I only have to work one job.
而且我只要白天工作
And I'll be working during the day.
感觉像是退休一样
It's going to feel like retirement.
也就是说我们每天放学后
So does this mean we don't have to be quiet
就不用保持安静啦?
every day when we come home from school?
6点前 想怎么大声就怎么大声
You can make all the noise you want, until 6:00.
嘿 爸爸 我们可以开始在超市买些名牌吗?
Hey, Dad, can we start buying name brands at the store now?
- 仅限奥利奥 - 真酷
- Just Oreos. - That's cool.
我们需要庆祝下
We  need to celebrate.
做些我们未曾做过的
Do something we've never done before.
意思是去看场电影后
That can mean anything from going to the movies
接着手拉着手回客厅
to holding hands in the living room.
嗨 爸爸 我们能去玩大逃亡吗?
Hey, Dad. Can we go to Great Escape?
游乐场?
The amusement park?
嗯 能去吗? 拜托啦
Yeah,  can we go? Please?
好吧 宝贝
Sure, baby.
真棒!
Yes!
我去告诉Chris
I got to tell Chris.
既然我妈妈不准我离开Corleone
Since my mother wouldn't let me leave Corleone,
我不得不疯狂的策划下
I had to take drastic measures.
你想让你自己被踢出去?
You're going to get yourself kicked out?
我不得不离开这儿
I have to get out of here.
还有别的选择吗?
What other choice do I have?
不知道
I don't know.
我只是有点舍不得你离开
I guess I just don't want you to go.
你把我一人丢在这儿
You leave me here by myself...
我就完了
I'm toast.
你会没事的
You'll be all right.
他们唯一来找你麻烦的理由 就是因为你跟我在屁股后面
The only reason why they mess with you is 'cause you hang out with me.
你会找交些新朋友啊
You'll find new friends.
但是我们小团队 哥们
But we're a team, man.
我们就像是《警界双雄》里得Starsky和Hutch
We're like Starsky and Hutch.
Hall和Oates (一白一黑二重唱组合)
Hall and Oates.
就像Itchy和Blacky
Like Itchy and Blacky.
我们还是朋友啊
We'll still be friends.
我只是在另个不同得学校里
I'll just be at a different school.
那么你觉得在另个学校会有不同吗?
So you think it's going to be different at the other school?
当然
Yeah.
真的不同
Real different.
嗨 你叫什么名字 小孩?
Hey, what's your name, kid?
- Chris - 你什么星座?
- Chris. - What's your sign?
双子
Gemini.
好吧 某个小酷猫在海上绕世界航行
All right. This cool cat sailed around the world
同船的还有Pinta和Santa Maria
on the Nia, Pinta and the Santa Maria.
如果你能拼出他的名字
I will give you a year's supply of Black Fro Sheen
我就给你提供1年的非洲黑人发型
if you can unscramble his name.
那么你是认真的?
So you're serious about this?
嗨 小侏儒
Hey, pygmy.
干啥?
What?
我是认真的
I'm serious.
我得离开这里
I got to get out of here.
妈妈 当我么去玩大逃亡得时候
Mama, when we go to the Great Escape,
我们可以骑"西部疯牛"吗?
can we get on the Neck Snapper?
不行 但是当你一坐上去
No, and if you get on the Neck Snapper,
接下来骑的时候 你会成为屁股胜利者
the next ride you'll be on will be the Butt Whupper.
而且Tonya你太小了
Besides, Tonya, you're too little.
Chris和我都才骑了两次
Chris and I are riding it twice.
仅仅在工作一天之后
After just one day on the job,
我爸带给家的不仅仅是更多的钱
my father was bringing home more than just a bigger paycheck.
天哪 那是什么?
God, what is that?
嗨 大家
Hey, everybody.
噢 天哪
Oh, my God.
Julius!
你卖了鱼还是和鱼美人睡过?
What? Are you selling the fish or sleeping with a mermaid?
怎么了?
What's wrong?
噢 Drew 去把窗户打开
Oh, Drew, go open up the windows.
快点 Tonya 去拿风扇
Hurry up, Tonya, go get the fans.
待会再给你做饭
I'll bring y'all dinner up to y'all later.
什么时候他们在自己房间吃饭了?
Since when do they get to eat in their room?
从你开始倒人胃口起
Since you turn people's stomachs.
你闻起来就像
You smell like...
馊掉的奶酪
pierced ears and cheese.
你不会每天都带着这臭味回家吧?
Are you going to come home smelling like this every day?
天哪!
My God!
不知道 但是我如果要这样
I don't know, but I if I do,
你们就习惯下吧
y'all just going to have to get used to it.
这份工作有非常多的补贴
This job has too many perks.
我该在怎么办啊?
What am I going to do with that?
你得带着你的小朋友上楼 然后给它洗澡
No, you need to take your little friend upstairs and put him in the shower.
要是它闻起来和你一样 我可不会烧它
'Cause if he smells anything like you, I ain't cooking him,
还有我肯定不会吃它
and I damn sure ain't eating him.
- 宝贝 - 走! 赶紧走!
- Baby. - Go! Just go!
你闻起来就像臭咖喱味的长统袜
You smell like curried tube socks.
赶紧走!
Just go!
第二天我实施我的踢出学校计划
The next day I set my plan to get kicked out of school into action.
Chris 应该是"H-E-R-E"
Chris, it's "H-E-R-E."
好好学习!
Study!
我从来都不会拼对
I never could spell.
不管啥艰难险阻
Come hell or high water,
我都一定要被赶出学校
I was getting kicked out of school.
噢! 谢谢你
Oh! Thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
再待这30秒得话 我们就比你还黑了
Another 30 seconds in there we would have been blacker than you.
我宣誓对国旗效忠...
I pledge allegiance to the flag...
这次有效了是吧?
This has got to work, right?
还有对美利坚合众国
...and to the republic for which it stands.
- 错! - 一个国家
- Wrong! - One nation...
真不敢相信这都不奏效
I couldn't believe that didn't work.
在做了几天少年惯犯后
After a few days of being a full-time juvenile delinquent,
我已经没辙了 仍然待在学校
I was out of ideas and still in school.
我放弃了 我再也不会离开这鬼地方了
I give up. I'm never getting out of here.
别这样 哥们
Come on, man.
这也不坏啊
It's not so bad.
再过段时间
Give  it some time.
事情会改变的
Things will change.
嘿 小熏肉 想去电动室吗?
Hey, bacon bit, want to go to the arcade?
我再不能忍受了!
I can't take this anymore!
耶!
Yes!
一本书砸到了我的挡风玻璃!
A book hit my windshield!
好吧 好消息是 我被踢出Corleone学校了
Well,  the good news is, I'm getting kicked out of Corleone.
坏消息是 我进了监狱!
The bad news is, I'm going to jail!
我这么费尽的设法被踢出学校
I was so busy trying to get kicked out of school,
没想到我也许活不到转校那天了
it never occured to me that I might not live long enough to transfer.
好吧 非常感谢
Okay, thank you very much.
你被退学了?
You got suspended?
只是场意外
It was an accident.
好吧 那么你是怎么意外的有了场意外?
Well, how can you accidentally have an accident?
一些孩子来找我的茬 所以我就拿我的书砸他
Some kid was messing with me, so I tried to hit him with my book.
Chris 如果你是读书而不是扔书的话
Chris, if you were reading the book instead of throwing the book,
也许他们就没空来找你的茬
maybe people wouldn't have time to mess with you.
他们总是抽时间来找我的茬
They always find time to mess with me.
我啥也甭想听了
I don't even want to hear it.
你也别想就躺在这儿
And don't think you just gonna be laying around here
看骑士骑术一整天 明白吗?
watching Knight Rider all day, okay?
你得在这儿做事 你得做家务
You're gonna be here working, you're gonna have chores.
你知道吗?
You know what?
上楼回你房间 然后等着你爸爸回来
Just go upstairs in your room and wait for your father to get here.
在我家
In our house,
"等你爸爸" 意思是会被给爆抽一顿
"Wait for your father" meant I was getting a whupping.
我爸爸对他的抽非常认真
My father took his whuppings very seriously.
他为每种错误都准备了皮带
He had a belt for every infraction.
这是"谎之皮带"
There was the Lying Belt,
这是"偷之皮带"
there was the Stealing Belt,
这是"又骗又偷皮带"
the Lying and Stealing Belt,
让某人怀孕的皮带
the Got Somebody Pregnant Belt.
最衰的是"吸毒皮带"
And the worst was the Doing Drugs Belt.
在我准备好受罚的时候
While I was getting ready for my punishment,
我妈也为我爸爸准备好了
my mother was getting ready for my father.
他如果以为他能走进这栋房子
He's crazy if he think he gonna...
闻起来像42街一样 那他就疯了
be... coming up in this house smelling it up like 42nd Street.
噢 不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no.
附近的邻居不会谈论我的
People in this neighborhood ain't gonna talk about... me.
Rochelle
Rochelle...
你在干嘛?
what you doing?
你的制服把整个屋子都熏臭了
Uniform was stinking up the whole house.
我都清理一整天了
I been cleaning up all day,
设法把这臭味给弄出去
trying to get that smell out of here.
但是这都是些啥?
But what's all this?
都是值16块大洋的保鲜膜啊
That's $16 worth of plastic wrap.
这是保护我家具的膜
This plastic is protecting my furniture.
到处都弥漫着鱼腥味
That fish smell was saturating everything.
噢 宝贝 你买了食品回来?
Oh, baby, you bought groceries?
我都还为你买了乌龟糖
I even got you the Turtles.
谢谢 宝贝
Thank you, baby.
嗷 嗷  乌龟糖 嗯!
Ooh, ooh, Turtles. Mmm!
这些乌龟糖吃起来像是海龟糖
These Turtles taste like... turtle.
我可不吃这些
I can't eat these.
好吧 那什么都别吃了
Fine. Don't eat any of 'em.
可那我有啥吃的?
But do I get something to eat?
不! 不!
No! No!
在你洗完澡之前没有
Not until you take a bath.
我可不想你熏坏我的保鲜膜
I do not want you smelling up my plastic.
接着 把你的衣服装进去
Here, put your clothes in there.
噢 在你做之前 我需要你去和Chris谈谈
Oh, and before you do that, I-I need you to talk to Chris.
什么事?
What happened?
他被退学了
He got suspended.
哦 不 我去让他尝尝我的鞭子
Oh, no. I'm gonna give him my belt...
别 别 别 别
No, no, no, no, no, no.
这次 我真的需要你和他谈谈
This time, I really need you to talk to him.
好吗?
O kay?
好的
Okay.
我爸爸闻起来实在是太臭了
My father smelled so bad,
我都不知道他是要抽死我 还是要熏死我
I didn't know if he was gonna beat me or suffocate me.
爸爸 在我们开始之前 你能把窗户打开吗?
Dad, before we start, can you open up a window?
不 这就当成是对你惩法的一部分
No. Consider this part of your punishment.
好吧
Okay.
说吧 儿子
Come on, man.
告诉我是咋会事
Tell me what's going on.
我恨那所学校 爸爸
I hate that school, Dad.
我恨那里的一切
I hate everything about it.
我知道妈妈想让我有个好点的教育
I know Mom wants me to get a good education,
但是每天都变得更糟
but every day, it just gets worse.
你不能因为不喜欢就放弃 Chris
You can't just quit something 'cause you don't like it, Chris.
但是妈妈总是放弃她的工作
But Mom quits her job all the time.
但是你是男子汉
But you're a man.
男子汉从不放弃
Men don't quit.
要是杰克・罗宾逊放弃了呢?
What if Jackie Robinson quit?
要是乔治・华盛顿放弃了呢?
What if George Washington Carver quit?
要是马丁路德・金放弃了呢?
What if Martin Luther King Jr. quit?
每当我爸爸有个话题想说的时候
When my father had a point to make,
他总是能起个虎头 结个蛇尾
he always started off strong, but he never ended that way.
要是桑德斯上校放弃了呢? (45分钟后)
What if Colonel Sanders quit?
要是阿波罗放弃了呢?
What if Apollo Creed quit?
要是凯瑟琳・杰克逊放弃生孩子了呢?
What if Katherine Jackson quit making kids?
难道她不是女人?!
Ain't she a woman?!
他们可能就是杰克逊老三 (著名歌手迈克・杰克逊 家族排行老三)
They might be The Jackson Three.
要是Kool from Kool和the Gang放弃了呢?
What if Kool from Kool and the Gang quit?
如果他们不叫The Gang
You think they would have gotten a record contract
你以为他们会得到唱片合同?
if they were just called The Gang?
直到今日 我都不能描述我爸爸所讲
To this day, I can't tell you what my father said
但是那臭味让我终身难忘
but that smell stayed with me forever.
要是你放弃 你就是让他们赢
If you quit, you're letting them win.
这不是关于赢还是输
It's not about winning or losing.
我只是想离开那学校
I just want to leave the school.
好吧
Okay, fine.
让我和你妈妈谈谈把你换所学校
Let me talk to your mother about getting you in a different school.
另个学校?!
Another school?!
每当Chris不喜欢什么 你都宠着他
If you bail Chris out every time he doesn't like something,
也就是说每当他有问题 他都会跑来找你
that means he's gonna run to you every time he has a problem.
也就是他怎么也学不会怎么做个男人
Which means he'll never learn how to be a man.
要是你不能教他怎么做个男人
And if you can't teach him how to be a man, that
也就是说你不是个称职的父亲
means you're a bad father.
要是你不是个称职的父亲
And if you're a bad father,
也就是说我挑了个错的丈夫
that means I picked the wrong husband.
要是你认为我会奔相走告的告诉这里的人
And if you think I'm about to let people run around here
我可以嫁给任何人
talking about I just marry anybody,
你一定是脑子秀逗了
you must be out your damn mind.
听着
Look...
噢 等等 不 等等!
Oh, wait, wait, no, wait!
先把塑料膜铺好
Put the plastic down first.
谢谢
Thank you.
听着 我知道你担心
Look, I know you're worried.
但是Chris在Corleone过的不开心啊
But Chris is just not happy at Corleone.
不好意思 我只是觉得桑福德不适合他
I'm sorry. I just don't think Sanford is good enough for him.
既然我有了新的工作
Well... now that I got this new job,
也许我们可以供的起他上学了
maybe we can afford to pay for him to go to school.
我们至少可以先看看
We could at least look around.
好吧
Okay, fine.
我们去找找其他的学校
We'll look for other schools.
我们还要去找找其他的肥皂 你个臭人!
And we'll look for other soap. You stink!
从那之后 我们试了表演艺术学校
From there, we tried performing arts school.
下一个!
Next!
我们去了犹太人学校
We looked into Hebrew school.
下一个!
Next!
我们甚至去了说唱学校
We even tried old school.
- 下一个! - 啥?
- Next! - What...?
打那之后 只剩一家可去了
After that, there was only one thing left to do.
我和你父亲讨论过了
Well, me and your father discussed it,
如果你真的想去附近的学校 那就去吧
and if you really want to go to the neighborhood school, you can.
真的?
For real?
是的 但是你得保证你的成绩上升
Yes, but you have to keep your grades up.
不是A 就是B
A's and B's.
如果你还想惹麻烦的话
And if you even think about getting in trouble,
我就会杀到那学校 然后一脚把你给废了
I  will march down to that school and knock the no-good out of you.
我们去Corleone取你的证件
We'll go to Corleone and pick up your papers.
在你缓刑期满了后 下周就转过去
You can transfer next week, after your suspension.
谢谢妈妈
Thanks, Ma.
嗯 我爱你
All right. I love you.
我成功了 接下来是我想象的
I did this, but here's what I felt like.
我离开这里了 笨蛋们!
I'm outta here, suckas!
我感觉爆爽的时候
I was feeling great.
与此同时 在大街上
Meanwhile, on the street,
大伙见了我爸就像毒贩见了警察一样 落荒而逃
my father was clearing folks out like a cop in a crack house.
真该死!
Something's dead!
妈妈 我不喜欢爸爸的新工作
Mama, I don't like Daddy's new job.
他臭啊!
He stinks!
是啊 不过他现在赚更多的钱了
Yeah, but he's making a lot more money now.
那又怎样? 他太臭了
So? He stinks.
他做别的工作的时候可不臭
He didn't stink when he worked his other jobs.
宝贝 有了这份工作 他可以有更多的时间来赔我们
Well, baby, with this job, he gets to spend more time with us.
更多的臭时间!
More stink time!
噢 好了 Tonya!
Oh, come on, Tonya!
没那么糟
It's not that ba...
你们都闻到了?!
Y'all smell that?!
嗯
Yeah.
该死 伙计! 你个臭人!
Damn, man! You stink!
噢 天哪!
Oh, Lord! Oh!
Rochelle?
Rochelle?!
- 干啥?! - 让我进来
- What?! - Let me in.
不 你的臭味
No. You smell.
那是一个工作人的气味
That's the smell of a working man.
不 那是海王大章鱼的气味
No, that is the smell of Aquaman.
Rochelle 开门
Rochelle, open the door.
不
No.
听着 宝贝
Look, baby,
我知道这份工作给你带来了更多的时间和钱
I understand that this job brings you more free time and more money,
但是我不能忍受的是
but I can't take it anymore.
孩子们都难以呼吸了
The kids can't breathe.
晚上我也不能入睡
I cannot sleep at night.
你不知道我每天都要去洗衣店吗?
Do you not know that I'm at that Laundromat every day?
我烧了这么多的香
I've been burning so much incense,
已经有十个人来我这买蚊香了
ten people came by here trying to buy reggae albums.
嘿 mon!
Hey, mon!
- 那你想让我怎样? - 放弃这份工作!
- What you want me to do? - Quit!
我不能放弃!
I can't just quit!
这会给孩子们树立个啥样的榜样?
What kind of example would that be for the kids, huh?
马歇尔放弃了吗?
Did Thurgood Marshall quit?
道格拉斯放弃了吗?
Did Frederick Douglass quit?
华盛顿放弃了吗?
Did Booker T. Washington quit?
我不知道 我也不管
I don't know, and I don't care.
我所知道的就是 我想要你放弃
All I know is, I want you to quit.
那带着孩子们去玩大逃亡怎样?
What about taking the kids to Great Escape, huh?
和你在一起 我们哪儿都不想去
We don't want to go nowhere with you.
是的 爸爸 你个臭男人
Yeah, Daddy, you stink.
- 这是啥? - 干净的衣服
- What's this? - Clean clothes.
我该在哪里换?
Where am I supposed to change?
我不知道
I don't know.
你干嘛不去问问这些猫?
Why don't you ask them cats?
同时 回到Corleone 就像是Kunta Kinte (由非洲贩运过来后在美国的生活)
Meanwhile, back at Corleone, like Kunta Kinte,
我正在等我的自由书
I was waiting for my freedom papers.
Greg!
嘿 哥们 你在这干嘛?
Hey, man. What are you doing here?
我妈妈来拿我的档案 我要去Sanford了
My mom came to get my transcript. I'm going to Sanford.
那么 你真的要走?
So, you're really gonna go?
- 嗯 - 哥们!
- Yeah. - Man!
至少你再也不用担心Caruso了
Well, at least you won't have to worry about Caruso anymore.
嗯 你过的还好吗?
Yeah. How are things going for you?
不知道 Caruso再也没来烦我了
I don't know. Caruso doesn't bother me anymore.
事实上 没人来烦我
In fact, nobody bothers me.
真是有几分寂寞
It's kind of lonely.
他真的是寂寞到去怀念屁股被踢
He must be really lonely to miss an ass whuppin'.
我要去上课了
Well, I got to go to class.
好吧 再见
All right. See ya.
嗯 再见
Yeah, see ya.
- 祝你好运 - 谢谢
- Good luck. - Thanks.
既然都差不多正式的了 接下来的一天
Since it was almost official, the next day,
我决定走到桑福德中学去
I decided to walk by Lamont Sanford,
去切身感受一下到我附近学校
to get a feel of what it was gonna be like
上学会是啥滋味
to go to school in my neighborhood.
该死! 他们也在这欺负弱小!
Damn! They got bullies here, too!
你看什么看?
What you looking at?
没啥 你们也在这上学?
Nothing. You guys go to school here?
是的 我在这儿上了16年了
Yeah. I've been going here for 16 years.
现在 小子我问你-- 你看什么看?
Now boy, I asked you a question-- what you looking at?
没啥
Nothing.
你说什么? 我们什么也不是?
So what you trying to say? We're nothing now?
我只是
I just...
我禁不住想起要是Greg也在这儿
I couldn't help but think that if Greg was here,
他可以帮我分担一半的痛揍
he could've taken half of this beating.
嗨 宝贝
Hi, baby.
做了你的晚餐
I made you dinner.
对你的工作我很抱歉
I'm sorry about your job.
我知道 我不敢相信我有了份好工作
I know. I can't believe I get one good job
几乎毁了我整个家
and it almost destroyed the whole family.
没关系 宝贝
It's okay, baby.
别担心 有天你会找份别的好工作的
Don't worry. You'll find another good job one day.
曾有份好工作却弄丢了
It's better to have had one good job and lost it,
比从没有份好工作要好的多
than to never have had one good job at all.
现在我有回到两份工作了
Now I'm back to two jobs.
嗯 现在他的第2份工作是哲学家
Yeah, now his second job is a philosopher.
怎么尝起来像是鱼腥味
That tastes like fish.
我告诉过你!
I told you!
回来整理你的锁柜?
Back to clean out your locker?
不是 我只是回来了
Nope. Just back for good.
酷!
Cool!
嘿 这可不是断背
Hey, this ain't Brokeback.
Greg!
对不起
Sorry.
那么 是什么让你决定回来的?
So, what made you decide to come back?
我想过Corleone是我的问题 但是随后我发现真正的问题
I thought Corleone was my problem, but then I noticed the real problem.
我又小 又是黑人 还不会打架
I'm little, skinny and I can't fight.
所以无论我去哪里 我还是我
So no matter where I go, I'm still the same guy.
他们揍了你
So, they jumped you.
嗯
Yeah.
我想认识的混球比不认识的要好的多
I figure the bully you know is better than the bully you don't.
嗨 大石头
Hey, Dolomite.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
没有你真糟糕
It was rough without you.
我不得不转去揍白人的孩子
I had to go back to beating up white kids.
下次你决定退出时
The next time you decide to quit,
可以让人知道吗?
could you let somebody know?
那么 我们现在该做啥?
So, what do we do now?
做我们经常做的
Same thing we always do.
欢迎你回来 哥们
Glad to have you back, man.
那天我意识到 无论我去哪所学校
That day I realized that no matter what school I went to,
事情都会变得一团糟糕
things were gonna be rough.
但是只要有Greg 事情都会好起来
But as long as I had Greg, things were gonna be all right.